<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no" ?>
<modDesc descVersion="104">
    <author>VertexDezign</author>
    <version>1.0.0.0</version>
    <title>
        <en>Additional Inputs</en>
        <de>Zusätzliche Eingaben</de>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[
Additional Inputs enhances your vehicle control in FS25 by adding explicit keybindings designed for realistic hardware setups,
such as the Moza Multi-function Stalks. This mod introduces authentic turn signal logic with comfort blinking (tip blink),
discrete controls for headlight and worklight stages, and dedicated inputs to Fold, Lower, and Activate implements
independently based on their front or back position without needing to select them first.

Features

Indicators / TurnSignal

Adds explicit inputs for indicating left / right and one for turning them off. Similar how an indicator lever in a car
works. Also adds the tip blink / comfort indicators functionality. If after the on signal an off signals follows within
500ms, the tip blink is activated.
If the hazard light is on, it has priority. These added inputs cannot turn of the hazard lights.


Lights

Adds new controls for normal front light on and off, also one for worklight front on.
The front light on action will also turn off the work light front. As this works best for me and the Moza Multi function
stalks. Translation from Moza Stalk lever turn to FS25

* OFF -> Front lights OFF
* parking light -> Front lights ON
* Front light -> Worklight Front ON

Also adds three additional Inputs related to the High Beam. One to turn the high beam on, one to trigger the high beam
flash (and also turn of the High Beam if turned on before) and one to release the flash.


Implements

Add Fold, Lower, and Activate inputs for implements attached at the front or back. They are not bound to the
current selected part of the vehicle.

More information regarding setup with Moza Stalks can be found on Github.
There you also find a detailed Table describing each input in detail.
Please report feedback or issues on Github.

GitHub link: https://github.com/VertexDezign/AdditionalInputs
]]>
        </en>
        <de><![CDATA[
Zusätzliche Eingaben verbessert die Fahrzeugsteuerung in FS25 durch explizite Tastaturbelegungen, die für realistische Hardware-Setups wie die Moza-Multifunktionshebel entwickelt wurden.
Dieser Mod bietet eine authentische Blinkerlogik mit Komfortblinken,
diskrete Steuerungen für Scheinwerfer- und Arbeitsscheinwerferstufen sowie dedizierte Eingaben zum Einklappen, Absenken und Aktivieren von Anbaugeräten,
unabhängig von ihrer vorderen oder hinteren Position, ohne dass diese zuvor ausgewählt werden müssen.

Funktionen

Blinker

Fügt explizite Eingaben für das Blinken von links/rechts und eine zum Ausschalten hinzu. Ähnlich wie ein Blinkerhebel in einem Auto
funktioniert. Fügt außerdem die Funktion „Tip Blink“ / Komfortblinken hinzu. Wenn nach dem Einschaltsignal innerhalb von
500 ms ein Ausschaltsignal folgt, wird „Tip Blink“ aktiviert.
Falls die Warnblinkanalge eingeschaltet ist, hat diese Vorrang und wird nicht ausgeschaltet über diese neuen Eingaben.


Belechtung

Fügt neue Steuerungen für das normale Ein- und Ausschalten des Frontlichts sowie eine für das Einschalten des Arbeitslichts vorne hinzu.
Durch das Einschalten des Frontlichts wird auch das Arbeitslicht vorne ausgeschaltet. Dies funktioniert für mich und die Moza-Multifunktionshebel am besten.
Übersetzung von Moza-Hebelbewegung zu FS25

* AUS -> Frontscheinwerfer AUS
* Standlicht -> Frontscheinwerfer EIN
* Frontscheinwerfer -> Front-Arbeitsscheinwerfer EIN

Fügt außerdem drei zusätzliche Eingänge für das Fernlicht hinzu. Einen zum Einschalten des Fernlichts, einen zum Auslösen der Lichthupe
(und zum Ausschalten des zuvor eingeschalteten Fernlichts) und einen zum Beenden der Lichthupe.


Anbaugeräte

Fügen Sie die Eingaben „Ausklappen“, „Heben/Senken“ und „Aktivieren“ für vorne oder hinten angebrachte Werkzeuge hinzu. Diese sind nicht an den
aktuell ausgewählten Teil des Fahrzeugs gebunden.

Weitere Informationen zur Einrichtung mit Moza Stalks finden Sie auf Github.
Dort finden Sie auch eine detaillierte Tabelle, in der jede Eingabe ausführlich beschrieben wird.
Bitte melden Sie Feedback oder Probleme auf Github.

GitHub-Link: https://github.com/VertexDezign/AdditionalInputs
]]>
        </de>
    </description>
    <iconFilename>icon_AI.png</iconFilename>
    <multiplayer supported="true"/>
    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="GrisuDebug.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="AI.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>

    <l10n filenamePrefix="l10n/l10n"/>

    <actions>
        <!-- indicators -->
        <action name="VD_AI_INDICATOR_LEFT_ON" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_INDICATOR_RIGHT_ON" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_INDICATOR_OFF" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <!-- light -->
        <action name="VD_AI_LOW_BEAM_ON" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_LOW_BEAM_OFF" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_FRONT_WORK_LIGHT_ON" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_HIGH_BEAM_ON" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_HIGH_BEAM_OFF_FLASH_TRIGGER" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_HIGH_BEAM_OFF_FLASH_RELEASE" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <!-- implements -->
        <action name="VD_AI_LOWER_FRONT" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_LOWER_BACK" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_FOLD_FRONT" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_FOLD_BACK" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_ACTIVATE_FRONT" category="VEHICLE"/>
        <action name="VD_AI_ACTIVATE_BACK" category="VEHICLE"/>
    </actions>

    <inputBinding>
        <actionBinding action="VD_AI_LOWER_FRONT">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lshift KEY_lctrl KEY_v"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="VD_AI_LOWER_BACK">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lalt KEY_lctrl KEY_v"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="VD_AI_FOLD_FRONT">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lshift KEY_lctrl KEY_x"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="VD_AI_FOLD_BACK">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lalt KEY_lctrl KEY_x"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="VD_AI_ACTIVATE_FRONT">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lshift KEY_lctrl KEY_b"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="VD_AI_ACTIVATE_BACK">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lalt KEY_lctrl KEY_b"/>
        </actionBinding>
    </inputBinding>


</modDesc>
